<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Lord haue mercy vpon vs A speciall remedy for the plague.</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1636</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 13 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 1 1-bit group-IV TIFF page image.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-12">2011-12 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A10603</idno>
            <idno type="STC">STC 20875</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC S105188</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99840917</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">99840917</idno>
            <idno type="VID">5461</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A10603)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 5461)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1475-1640 ; 934:16)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>Lord haue mercy vpon vs A speciall remedy for the plague.</title>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet ([1] p.)   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed [by R. Young and M. Flesher] for M. S[parke] Junior,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[London] :</pubPlace>
                  <date>[1636]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>With plague statistics for 1603, 1625 and 1636.</note>
                  <note>British Library copy has printed totals through 9 June 1636; Guildhall Library (London) copy through 16 June--STC.</note>
                  <note>Printers' and bookseller's names and publication date from STC.</note>
                  <note>Imperfect; torn at foot, affecting text.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of the original in the British Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Plague --  England --  London --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-08</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2007-08</date>
            <label>Aptara</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-04</date>
            <label>John Latta</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-04</date>
            <label>John Latta</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-06</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="reports">
            <pb facs="tcp:5461:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <head>LORD
haue mercy
vpon vs.<figure>
                  <figDesc>decorative border</figDesc>
               </figure>
            </head>
            <epigraph>
               <q>
                  <p>O Death I will bee thy death:
O Hell I will be thy victory.</p>
                  <p>Thou ſhalt not bee affraid of
the Peſtilence that walketh
in darkneſſe, nor the Plague
that deſtroyeth at noone
day.</p>
                  <p>I have ſinned, O thou Preſ<gap reason="illegible: missing" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>
ver of men: I ſhall goe
the grave, and ſhall returne
no more.</p>
                  <p>Watch &amp; pray, for you know
not when the Lord will
come.</p>
               </q>
            </epigraph>
            <list>
               <head>A true Report
of ſuch as were
buried of the
plague, from the
31. of March
1603. to the 22.
of Decem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ber.</head>
               <item>March 31.—6</item>
               <item>April 7.—4</item>
               <item>April 14.—4</item>
               <item>April 21.—8</item>
               <item>April 28.—10</item>
               <item>May 5.—11</item>
               <item>May 12.—12</item>
               <item>May 19.—22</item>
               <item>May 26.—32</item>
               <item>June 2.—30</item>
               <item>June 9.—43</item>
               <item>June 16.—59</item>
               <item>June 23.—72</item>
               <item>June 30.—158</item>
               <item>July 7.—263</item>
               <item>July 14.—424</item>
            </list>
            <list>
               <head>This week were
the our Pariſhes
joyned with the
City and Li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>berties.</head>
               <item>July 21.—917</item>
               <item>July 28.—1396</item>
               <item>Aug. 4.—1922</item>
               <item>Aug. 11.—1745</item>
               <item>Aug. 18.—2713</item>
               <item>Aug. 25.—2539</item>
               <item>Sept. 1.—3035</item>
               <item>Sep 8.—2724</item>
               <item>Sept. 15.—2818</item>
               <item>Sept. 22.—2195</item>
               <item>Sept. 29.—1732</item>
               <item>Octob. 6.—1641</item>
               <item>Octo. 13.—1149</item>
               <item>Octob 20.—642</item>
               <item>Octob. 27.—508</item>
               <item>Nov. 3.—594</item>
               <item>Nov. 10.—442</item>
               <item>Nov. 17.—251</item>
               <item>Nov. 24.—105</item>
               <item>Decem. 1.—102</item>
               <item>Decem. 8.—55</item>
               <item>Decem. 15.—96</item>
               <item>Decem. 22.—79</item>
            </list>
            <list>
               <head>Anno 1624 bu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ried
of the
Plague as fol<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>loweth.</head>
               <item>June 2. 69.</item>
               <item>June 9.—91.</item>
               <item>June 16.—165.</item>
               <item>June 23.—239.</item>
               <item>June 30.—390.</item>
               <item>July 7.—593.</item>
               <item>July 14.—10<gap reason="illegible: blotted" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>4.</item>
               <item>July 21.—18<gap reason="illegible: blotted" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>9</item>
               <item>July 28.—2471</item>
               <item>Aug. 4.—3659</item>
               <item>Aug. 11.—411<gap reason="illegible: blotted" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>
               </item>
               <item>Aug. 18.—4463</item>
               <item>Aug. 25.—4218</item>
               <item>Sept. 1.—3344</item>
               <item>Sept 8.—2550</item>
               <item>Sept. 19.—1672</item>
               <item>Sept. 22.—1551</item>
               <item>Sept. 29.—852</item>
               <item>Octob. 6.—538</item>
               <item>Octob. 13.—511</item>
               <item>Octob. 20.—331</item>
               <item>Octob. 27.—134</item>
               <item>Novemb. 3.—89</item>
               <item>Novem. 10.—92</item>
               <item>Novem. 17.—48</item>
               <item>Novem. 24.—17</item>
               <item>Decem. 1.—15</item>
            </list>
            <list>
               <head>This yeer 1636
were buried of
the Plague as
followeth.</head>
               <item>April 7.—2</item>
               <item>April 14.—4</item>
            </list>
            <list>
               <head>Here is added
unto the reſt,
S. Marg. Weſtm.
Lambeth.
S. Mary Newin.
Redriffe Pariſh.
S. Mary Iſlingt.
Stepney Pariſh.
Hackney Pariſh.</head>
               <item>April 21.—14</item>
               <item>April 28.—17</item>
               <item>May 5.—10</item>
               <item>May 12.—55</item>
               <item>May 19.—35</item>
               <item>May 26.—62</item>
               <item>June 2.—67</item>
               <item>June 9.—87</item>
               <item>June 16.</item>
               <item>June 23</item>
               <item>June 30.</item>
               <item>July 7.</item>
               <item>July 14.</item>
               <item>July 21.</item>
               <item>July 28.</item>
               <item>Aug 4.</item>
               <item>Aug. 11.</item>
               <item>Aug. 18.</item>
               <item>Aug 25.</item>
               <item>Sept. 1.</item>
               <item>Sept. 8.</item>
               <item>Sept. 15.</item>
               <item>Sept. 22.</item>
               <item>Sept. 29.</item>
               <item>Octob. 6.</item>
               <item>Octo. 13.</item>
               <item>Octo. 20.</item>
               <item>Octo. 27.</item>
               <item>Nove. 3.</item>
               <item>Nov. 10.</item>
               <item>Nov 17.</item>
               <item>Nov. 24.</item>
               <item>Decem. 1.</item>
            </list>
         </div>
         <div type="treatise">
            <head>1636</head>
            <list>
               <head>Preſervati<gap reason="illegible: faint" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap> from Infection.</head>
               <item>
                  <gap reason="illegible: missing" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap> By Smell.</item>
               <item>2. By Drinke.</item>
               <item>3. By Food.</item>
            </list>
            <list>
               <head>Preſervative when infected.</head>
               <item>4. By ſweating.</item>
               <item>5. By ripening the Sore.</item>
               <item>6. By ayring Clothes.</item>
            </list>
            <div type="part">
               <head>By Smell.</head>
               <p>TAke white Sponge ſoaked in herbe of grace water, which
water is thus made: Take a quart of Vinegar, halfe a pint of
Roſe-water, put in a hand-full of Rue, and halfe an handfull of
worme-wood, and boile it to a pint: then take and dip the Spunge
in it when it is cold, and hold it to your noſe when you go abroad:
and this is a good Preſervative.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <head>Aliter.</head>
               <p>TAke of the beſt Cedar wood, and grate a ſmall wooden boxe
full, and let the lid be full of holes, and ſmell to it.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <head>By Drinke.</head>
               <p>TAke worme-wood, and herbe of grace, and ſteepe them all
night in a pint of beere, with a lemmon ſliced, and drink them
in the morning faſting.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <head>By Food.</head>
               <p>TAke a Wal-nut kernell, a corne of ſalt, foure leaves of herbe
of grace; cut all very ſmall, and put them in a blue figge, and
roaſt it; and faſt one houre after: but uſe it daily.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <head>Aliter</head>
               <p>TAke a toſte of bread, and ſpread it ouer with Treacle and but<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter,
and herbe of grace eaten with it is very good.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <head>By Sweat.</head>
               <p>TAke Endive water a quart, Century water a pint, Ivie berries halfe
an hand-full bruiſed. Boile theſe together gently a quarter of an
houre, and when you take it from the fire, diſſolve therein as much
Treacle as a Nut, and a little Sugar, alſo put thereunto three ſpoonefuls
of Vinegar. As ſoone as the Patient doth complaine, and Nature being
yet ſtrong, give him faſting one good draught thereof warme, and let
him keepe his bed, and ſweat ten houres, or leſſe, as the ſtrength of the
Patient will beare. In his ſweating give him now and then Ale clarified,
and into every draught put two or three ſpoone-fuls of the decoction.
When he riſeth, give him ſome broth, not made over ſtrong, neither
with much ſpice: and be very carefull to keep him from the ayre. This
decoction thus uſed will either force out the Sore, or elſe if the Patient
ſweat throughly well, cure him without any Sore. And if thou find he
be not greatly eaſed within eight houres after his ſweating, the next day
uſe the like order.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <head>To ripen the Sore.</head>
               <p>TAke of cloves of garlick 18. penny weight, of freſh butter 3. ounces,
of lemon the weight of a ſhilling, a white onion cut in pieces, a hand<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>full
of malloes, and a hand-full of ſcallions; boil theſe in a pottell of wa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter,
and make of them a poultis, and lay to the Sore very warm. Renew it
every day.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <head>Aliter.</head>
               <p>TAke a hot loafe newly drawne, and lay to it, but when you take it
away lay a freſh, but be ſure to burie the bread after.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <head>By Airing.</head>
               <p>TO aire a houſe, take Cedar or Juniper, Lavender, and dry Bayes, and
old Roſemary, put them on a pan of coales in the middle of a houſe.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <head>To aire beds, or cloaths.</head>
               <p>TAke the ſame with Roſe-water and Vinegar, &amp; lay the Bed upon an
hurdell, or frame of a table, with ſtaves to ſtay it up, and ſet two or
three Chaſing diſhes under: &amp; this is an excellent receit to aire clothes.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <head>A ſpeciall meanes to preſerve health.</head>
               <p>FIrſt, faſt and pray, and then take a quart of Repentance of <hi>Ninive,</hi> and put in two
hand-fuls of Faith in the blood of Chriſt, with as much Hope and Charity as you
can get, and put it into the veſſell of a clean Conſcience: then boyle it on the fire of
Love, ſo long till you ſee by the eye of Faith, the black foame of the love of this world
ſtinke in your ſtomacke, then ſcumme it off cleane with the ſpoone of faithfull Pray<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ers.
When that is done, put in the powder of Patience, &amp; take the cloth of Chriſts
Innocency, and ſtraine all together in his Cup: then drinke it burning hot next
thy heart, and cover thee warme with as many clothes of Amendment of life as God
ſhall ſtrengthen thee to beare, that thou mayſt ſweate out all the poyſon of covetouſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſſe,
pride, whoredome, idolatrie, uſury, ſwearing, lying, and ſuch like. And when
thou feeleſt thy ſelfe altered from the forenamed vices, take the powder of Say-well,
and put it upon thy tongue: but drinke thrice as much Doe-well daily. Then take
the oyle of good Workes, and annoint therewith thine eyes, eares, heart, and
hands, that they may be ready and nimble to miniſter unto the poore members of
Chriſt. When that is done, then in Gods name ariſe from ſinne willingly, take up
Chriſts Croſſe boldely, ſtand unto it manfully, beare it patiently, and reſt thankful<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly,
and thou ſhalt live everlaſtingly, and come to heaven ſafely. To which place ha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſten
us, Lord, ſpeedily. Amen.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="poem">
               <head>The Brevity of mans Life, as well by reaſon of this, as all other Diſeaſes.</head>
               <lg>
                  <l>LIke to the Damaske Roſe you ſee,</l>
                  <l>Or like the bloſſome on the Tree,</l>
                  <l>Or like the dainty flower of May,</l>
                  <l>Or like the morning to the day,</l>
                  <l>Or like the ſunne, or like the ſhade,</l>
                  <l>Or like the Gourd that Jonas had:</l>
                  <l>Even ſuch is Man, whoſe threed is ſpun,</l>
                  <l>Drawn out, and cut, and ſo is done.</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible: paper torn" extent="1 span">
                        <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                     </gap> the Bloſſome blaſteth,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible: paper torn" extent="1 span">
                        <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                     </gap>
                  </l>
                  <l>The graſſe withers, the tale is ended,</l>
                  <l>The Bird is flown, the Deaw's aſcended,</l>
                  <l>The houre is ſhort, the ſpan not long,</l>
                  <l>The Swan's neer death, Mans life is done.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Like to the Bubble in the Brooke.</l>
                  <l>Or in a Glaſſe much like a Looke.</l>
                  <l>Or like a Shuttle in Weavers hand,</l>
                  <l>Or like a writing on the ſand,</l>
                  <l>Or like a thought, or like a dreame,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible: paper torn" extent="1 span">
                        <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                     </gap> of the ſtreame:</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible: paper torn" extent="1 span">
                        <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                     </gap>
                  </l>
                  <l>Or like a race, or like a Goale,</l>
                  <l>Or like the dealing of a dole:</l>
                  <l>Even ſuch is man, whoſe brittle ſtate</l>
                  <l>Is alwaies ſubject unto fare.</l>
                  <l>The Arrowes ſhot, the flood ſoon ſpent,</l>
                  <l>The time no time, the web ſoone rent,</l>
                  <l>The race ſoone run, the Goale ſoon won,</l>
                  <l>The Dole ſoon dealt, Mans life is done.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Like to the lightning from the skye,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible: blotted" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap> like a Poſte that quick doth hye,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible: blotted" extent="1 span">
                        <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                     </gap> ſhort long,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible: paper torn" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>like a tourney three dayes long,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible: paper torn" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> like the ſhow when Summer's come,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible: paper torn" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> like a Peare, or like a Plum:</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible: paper torn" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>en ſuch is man, who heaps up ſorrow,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible: paper torn" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>es but this day, and dyes to morrow.</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible: paper torn" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>e lightning's paſt, the Poſt muſt goe,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible: paper torn" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>he ſong is ſhort, the journey's ſo,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible: paper torn" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>he Peare doth rot, the Plum doth fall,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible: paper torn" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>e Snow diſſolves, and ſo muſt all.</l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <div type="poem">
               <head>Of mans reſurrection.</head>
               <l>LIke to the Seed put in Earths womb,</l>
               <l>Or like dead <hi>Lazarus</hi> in his tomb,</l>
               <l>Or like <hi>Tabitha</hi> being aſleep,</l>
               <l>Or <hi>Jonas</hi>-like, within the Deep,</l>
               <l>Or like the Night or Starres by day,</l>
               <l>Which ſeeme to vaniſh cleane away:</l>
               <l>Even ſo this Death Mans life bereaves,</l>
               <l>But being dead, Man death deceaves.</l>
               <l>The Seed it ſpringeth, <hi>Lazarus</hi> ſtandeth;</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>Tabitha</hi> walks, and <hi>Jonas</hi> landeth:</l>
               <l>The Night is paſt, the Starres remain:</l>
               <l>So Man that dyes ſhall live againe.</l>
            </div>
            <div type="to_the_reader">
               <p>Reader, I referre thee for thy better preſer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vation,
to the 4<gap reason="illegible: faint" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>. Prayer in the <hi>Crums of com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fort,</hi>
being moſt effectuall, with Remembrance
of Deliberance, at the latter end of the books:
and to ſing in times of heavineſſe Pſalmes <gap reason="illegible: blotted" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>8.
&amp; 91 &amp;c.</p>
               <p>
                  <figure>
                     <figDesc>decorative border</figDesc>
                  </figure>
               </p>
            </div>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="colophon">
            <p>
               <hi>Printed for</hi> M. S. Junior.</p>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>
